<sequential display_name="Time management and invoices">
  <vertical display_name="Introduction" url_name="time_management_and_invoices_introduction">
    <html url_name="time_management_and_invoices_introduction_1">
      <p>
        In this part we'll cover time management and how invocing works for OpenCraft. Let's start!
      </p>
    </html>
  </vertical>
  <vertical display_name="Time management" url_name="time_management_and_invoices_time_management">
    <html url_name="time_management_and_invoices_time_management_1">
      <p>
        The way we track time has an effect on our productivity. Each person
        tends to find their own comfort zone here, depending on their setup, their work
        habits, etc.. This section should shed some light on different methods of time
        management and time tracking used by some on the team, to help you in working
        out what may be optimal for yourself.
        <br />
        <br />
        To help you in dealing with the potential mysteries revolving
        around tracking and managing their time in the several different types of tasks
        and activities here at OpenCraft, we've compiled a QA section
        with the most common queries from past newcomers.
      </p>
      <p>
        Q: Do I need to use the time tracker app on JIRA?
      </p>
      <blockquote>
        <p>
          A: No! As you'll read from our team's personal tips (in the next unit),
          there are only a few people on the team that actually use JIRA's plugin
          for time tracking. However, because it's directly in JIRA, it won't necessitate
          the extra step of transfering work logs, so give it a try in case it ends up
          being perfectly fine for you!
        </p>
      </blockquote>
      <p>
        Q: How precise does tracked time need to be?
        (Is a quarter hour sufficient if not using the time tracker?)
      </p>
      <blockquote>
        <p>
          For tracking time in sprint planning, if you look at specific epics
          you should assign this time to the epics themselves (splitting
          roughly over a given period of time, it doesn't need to be 100% exact).
          Or on the tickets themselves if you read them. For things like the meeting itself,
          or things in sprint planning that aren't related to any epic, there is OC-515,
          but it should be kept to a minimum, since we can't differentiate which projects
          the time logged on that epic was spent on, which makes it difficult
          to properly invoice clients afterwards.
        </p>
        <p>
          It's good in general to be precise about time logging - whenever possible,
          use the exact measurement from the tracker - it's not uncommon
          to be surprised by the amount of time we spend on specific tasks
          once we start tracking it. However, to keep the amount of time spent logging
          time sane, when you work for short amount of times switching between
          a set of tasks or epics, it can become difficult to use a timer efficiently
          - you can then divide the time roughly - you look at how much time
          you've spent in total (say, 1h), and if you spent roughly
          the same amount of time on each of say 6 tasks/epics,
          you can log 10min on each. It's not too bad if it's isn't completely
          exact on very small amounts - it will average out eventually.
        </p>
      </blockquote>
      <p>
        Q: Where do I track time for sprint planning or really small tasks?
      </p>
      <blockquote>
        <p>
          On the tasks or epics for which you spent time planning/grooming.
          For example, for the Enterprise team, if you spend time in the grooming meeting,
          track that time on the Enterprise epic.
        </p>
      </blockquote>
      <p>
        Q: How often (and when) should we invoice OpenCraft, and when can I expect payment?
        What details should be included in the invoice?
      </p>
      <p>
      </p>
      <blockquote>
        <p>
          You'll learn about it soon in details in
          <a href="/jump_to_id/time_management_and_invoices_invoices">
            another unit
          </a> of this section.
        </p>
      </blockquote>
    </html>
  </vertical>
  <vertical display_name="Tips from the team members" url_name="time_management_and_invoices_tips_from_the_team_members">
    <html url_name="time_management_and_invoices_tips_from_the_team_members_1">
      <p>
        Members of the team were kind enough to share their personal techniques/habits
        for tracking time - almost everyone who shared seemed to have something unique!
      </p>
    </html>
    <html url_name="time_management_and_invoices_tips_from_the_team_members_2">
      <h3>Brandon</h3>
      <blockquote>
        <p>
          I use
          <a href="https://github.com/projecthamster/hamster" target="_blank">Project Hamster</a>,
          which I find has a very quick, easy, reliable interface. It's a GTK
          project, but I believe it's tightly integrated with other components in the
          freedesktop/GNOME ecosystem, so it would probably be difficult if not impossible
          to make it work outside of Linux or FreeBSD.
        </p>
        <p>
          Either way, I imagine there are plenty of tools that do just as good
          a job for Windows or macOS.
        </p>
        <p>
          My usual pattern is this:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>
            For keeping track of larger tasks during the day (things I think
            will take &gt; 10-15 minutes), I track these directly with Hamster.
            I actually copy and paste the full name of the OpenCraft ticket
            into Hamster when I start logging; this makes logging the time on JIRA
            much easier later on.
          </li>
          <li>
            I try to remain at Inbox Zero as much as possible, so I respond
            to most small things immediately, prioritize my email as a task list
            for stuff I choose not to respond to immediately (usually when
            they're bigger notifications), and clear out the bigger notifications in
            between tasks (for this, it helps to use
            <a href="https://inbox.google.com/" target="_blank">Google Inbox</a>
            instead of Gmail, although there are some downsides to it
            and the OpenCraft org itself doesn't have Inbox enabled).
          </li>
          <li>
            For the smaller email notifications (usually &lt; 10 minutes),
            I log my time directly on the corresponding JIRA tickets right away
            using the 'W' hotkey and tabbing through the fields.
            It takes no time at all to enter worklogs this way, and there's no point
            in tossing this stuff into Hamster since they're so small.
          </li>
          <li>
            At the end of my day, I go to the
            <a href="https://tasks.opencraft.com/secure/TempoUserView.jspa" target="_blank">Worklog Calendar</a>
            view In JIRA and record all the time I have recorded in OpenCraft.
          </li>
        </ul>
      </blockquote>
    </html>
    <html url_name="time_management_and_invoices_tips_from_the_team_members_3">
      <h3>Braden</h3>
      <blockquote>
        <p>
          I use
          <a href="https://toggl.com/" target="_blank">toggl</a>
          because it's really simple and flexible to use (compared to Tempo),
          and then at the end of each day I use the Worklog Calendar view in Tempo
          to copy my time entries over into Tempo.
        </p>
        <p>
          I generally start a timer on toggl, then work for a bit on a bunch of related work,
          then go back to toggl and enter a quick note about which task/epic I worked on
          and what I did. What I like about toggl is that it's easy
          to retroactively split up time entries if it turned out to be more than one project.
        </p>
        <p>
          I get a lot of emails from many different projects that we work on,
          so I have filters that automatically label (most) emails by client,
          and then I usually go through my emails client by client.
          So I'll read all the McKinsey emails, then record a time entry for that,
          then read all the Management emails, then record a time entry for that, etc.
          That makes it easier to track my time per epic, and since I do it per-client
          and not per-epic, the labelling itself is not too much admin overhead.
        </p>
        <p>
          <a href="https://github.com/open-craft/documentation/blob/master/images/braden-time-tracking.png" target="_blank"><img src="https://github.com/open-craft/documentation/raw/master/images/braden-time-tracking.png" alt="Screenshot of Braden's gmail with automatically-added tags" /></a>
        </p>
      </blockquote>
    </html>
    <html url_name="time_management_and_invoices_tips_from_the_team_members_4">
      <h3>Sven</h3>
      <blockquote>
        <p>
          I do more or less what Brandon does, except that I use
          <a href="http://www.k5n.us/gtimer.php?topic=Screenshots" target="_blank">GTimer</a>
          instead of Hamster. It's quite simple, but rather idiosyncratic,
          and the only reason I'm using it is because the Xubuntu Hamster package
          was broken at the time I looked for a time tracking tool
          and I could not be bothered to compile it myself.
        </p>
        <p>
          For small tasks, I just start a stopwatch on my phone and enter the time
          directly into Jira once I'm done. This may seem somewhat crude,
          but it's still a lot better than the Tempo time tracker on Jira.
        </p>
      </blockquote>
    </html>
    <html url_name="time_management_and_invoices_tips_from_the_team_members_5">
      <h3>Uman</h3>
      <blockquote>
        <p>
          I've tried to use an external application like others once,
          and I quickly felt that the process of copying over work logs
          all the time wasn't for me.
        </p>
        <p>
          So instead, for large tasks, I often take a look at the current time
          through the phone or clock, and come back to it later
          when I feel like my task is done, and track the difference. For smaller tasks,
          I usually have a good idea of how long it'll take (i.e. 3-5 minutes),
          and don't bother with the overhead of a timer in these cases.
        </p>
        <p>
          A funny reminder for these timers: I've awkwardly forgotten in the past
          to log my time for the task while running the timer, and when I come back
          the next day there's 24+ hours of time ticking along. Don't forget to track it!
        </p>
        <p>
          As for general time management, I don't think this technique will be useful
          for most people, but for me: I essentially make a mental or written down plan
          of how I'll execute my tasks for the week at the beginning.
          I then tackle each task at appropriate times depending on how much I believe
          each should take based off of my planning. This used to be impossible
          without having context with the task's content, but over time
          it's becoming pretty clear to me the path these things generally take.
        </p>
      </blockquote>
    </html>
    <html url_name="time_management_and_invoices_tips_from_the_team_members_6">
      <h3>Matjaz</h3>
      <blockquote>
        <p>
          I tried using time trackers in the past, but it didn't work for me.
          I found it was too much overhead to switch the tracker every 5 minutes
          when answering another mail. I would also often forget to start, stop,
          or switch to a different customer when switching projects, so now I just do it
          manually. The fact that I start working at the same time every day makes it
          easier (don't have to remember to check the clock every time when I start:)).
        </p>
        <p>
          In order to keep things manageable, I log time in 0.5 hour chunks.
          I don't keep track of each individual 5 minute email -
          if I'm answering emails for 30 minutes, I will log all 30 minutes
          to the client for which I spent most of that 30 minutes.
          In theory the logged time should even up over time.
        </p>
      </blockquote>
    </html>
    <html url_name="time_management_and_invoices_tips_from_the_team_members_7">
      <h3>Tips and tricks for working remotely</h3>
      <p>
        There is also a
        <a href="https://forum.opencraft.com/t/working-remotely-tips-and-tricks/112/">forum post</a>
        where everyone posted tips and tricks. You are welcome to post your own tricks too!
      </p>
    </html>
  </vertical>
  <vertical display_name="Contact sheet" url_name="time_management_and_invoices_contact_sheet">
    <html url_name="time_management_and_invoices_contact_sheet_1">
    <p>
      Please fill the
      <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/107dR9H1vWjLpJlXPuBaFJIFaEPEmaSh50xLow_aEGVw/edit" target="_blank">contact sheet</a>.
    </p>
    <p>
      It includes fields like <em>availability</em>, which allows
      to get an idea of the best time to talk to that person.
    </p>
    <p>
      It's not precise work hours btw - just when you are better able
      to monitor for pings for example.
    </p>
    </html>
  </vertical>
  <vertical display_name="Invoices" url_name="time_management_and_invoices_invoices">
    <html url_name="time_management_and_invoices_invoices_1">
      <p>
        Invoices are generated automatically by Crafty (our bot). Crafty will be generating the invoice based on the hours you have logged on JIRA.
      </p>
    </html>
    <html url_name="time_management_and_invoices_invoices_2">
      <h3>
        <strong>When is the invoice generated?</strong>
      </h3>
      <blockquote>
        <p>
          Crafty sends a reminder on the last day of the month, to remind you to log all your time on JIRA.
          Then it generates the invoice on the 3rd day of the month, and sends you an email with a link to approve it.
        </p>
      </blockquote>
    </html>
    <html url_name="time_management_and_invoices_invoices_3">
      <h3>
        <strong>When can I expect payment?</strong>
      </h3>
      <blockquote>
        <p>
          The transfer should arrive before the 15th of the month - often earlier,
          but do note that we have had bank delays at times.
          Any issues should be communicated with <code>billing@opencraft.com</code>.
        </p>
      </blockquote>
    </html>
    <html url_name="time_management_and_invoices_invoices_4">
      <h3>
        <strong>What details are needed by OpenCraft to make the payment?</strong>
      </h3>
      <blockquote>
        <p>Make sure you send this information to Xavier by <a href="mailto:xavier@opencraft.com">email</a>:
          <ol>
            <li>Company Name</li>
            <li>VAT</li>
            <li>IBAN</li>
            <li>SWIFT</li>
            <li>Account Number</li>
            <li>Any other applicable details</li>
          </ol>
          The entity holding the account and its address must match the address for you in your contract.
        </p>
      </blockquote>
    </html>
  </vertical>
</sequential>
